# TRESTAN JANOS GARCIA

0912-921-3568 General Lim, Orion, Bataan garcia.trestanjanos@gmail.com



## **SUMMARY**

A goal-oriented professional with a wide range of experience from different fields but has expertise in software development. Driven with curiosity, I can easily adapt to new environments and acquire new skills because I know I can excel in whatever I put myself into.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Tutor Sep 2023 - May 2024

- Prepared advance lessons that is beneficial to the learner's educational growth, resulting in a better class standing.
- Provided guidance in doing the learner's homework, activities and projects, ensuring a correct output.
- Advocated for expressing the learner's thoughts and ideas through critical thinking.

## Senior High School Internship, MCP Construction

Nov 2017 - Dec 2017

- Studied blueprints of buildings to make a proper estimate of materials and its costing.
- Performed site inspections to observe the construction process.
- Performed other office tasks assigned by the supervisor.

### **PROJECTS**

## **ICS Online Library System Project**

Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

CMSC 128: Introduction to Software Engineering Class, Institute of Computer Science - UPLB

- Headed the Backend Team providing leadership through task distribution and implementation.
- Participated in the design of the library system ensuring its efficiency and functionality.
- Performed system testing to ensure the software is error-free.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Communication Skills Organized and Efficient	Problem Solving Skills Attention to details	Leadership Skills Time Management	
TECHNICAL SKILLS			
C, C++, Python, Java, R Microsoft Office Suite	Object-Oriented Programming JavaScript, NodeJS	Basic HTML and CSS Adobe Creative Suite	

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - Undergraduate**

Aug 2018 - Dec 2021

University of the Philippines Los Baños

• Relevant coursework in computer programming and software development.

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Languages: English, Filipino

• Certifications: Civil Service Eligible - Professional

Accomplishments: Dean's Lister (2018-2021)